<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[David Moody's Blog]]></title><description><![CDATA[David Moody's Blog]]></description><link>http://davidxmoody.com</link><generator>metalsmith-feed</generator><lastBuildDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2014 10:24:45 GMT</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://davidxmoody.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title><![CDATA[Building a blog with Metalsmith]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>I recently transitioned this blog from <a href="http://jekyllrb.com/">Jekyll</a> to <a href="http://www.metalsmith.io/">Metalsmith</a>. I&#39;m glad I started with Jekyll but I wanted more control. I decided to switch to Metalsmith so that I could write my own build scripts in a language I knew (JavaScript). </p>
<p>There are <em>tons</em> of excellent static site generators available. See <a href="https://staticsitegenerators.net/">staticsitegenerators.net</a> for a list. I&#39;ve used <a href="https://docpad.org/">DocPad</a> before (for the <a href="http://professorp.co.uk/">professorp.co.uk</a> website). I chose Metalsmith because it offered the most bare-bones setup with minimal restrictions. </p>
<p>This post will not be a full guide on how to use Metalsmith. I&#39;m assuming that anyone interested in Metalsmith is willing to get their hands dirty. Instead, this post will simply list some of the useful plugins I&#39;ve come across and some other hacks I&#39;ve made up. </p>
<p><a href="http://davidxmoody.com/building-a-blog-with-metalsmith/">Read 16 remaining paragraphs...</a></p>]]></description><link>http://davidxmoody.com/building-a-blog-with-metalsmith/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://davidxmoody.com/building-a-blog-with-metalsmith/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[CloudFlare and hashed CSS]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>One of the main advantages of static sites is supposed to be faster load times. However, I noticed this blog was still taking longer than expected to load. </p>
<p>I discovered <a href="http://davidensinger.com/2014/04/transferring-the-dns-from-namecheap-to-cloudflare-for-github-pages/">this post by David Ensinger</a> in which he describes the same problem. I&#39;ve learned a lot from his other posts and we appear to have pretty similar setups. The problem he describes is a time consuming 302 redirect caused by using GitHub Pages with a DNS <code>A</code> record. I suggest you look at his post for more details. </p>
<p><a href="http://davidxmoody.com/cloudflare-and-hashed-css/">Read 16 remaining paragraphs...</a></p>]]></description><link>http://davidxmoody.com/cloudflare-and-hashed-css/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://davidxmoody.com/cloudflare-and-hashed-css/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Host any static site with GitHub Pages]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://pages.github.com/">GitHub Pages</a> is pretty awesome. It provides free, no-hassle hosting for static sites built with <a href="http://jekyllrb.com/">Jekyll</a>. However, it also has some limitations.</p>
<p>For example, although Jekyll &quot;supports&quot; tags, you can&#39;t create pages to list all posts with a given tag. At least not without using a plugin, which GitHub Pages doesn&#39;t allow.</p>
<p>There is an easy way around this. You can build the site locally (using any plugins or code you want) and still host it on GitHub Pages. It&#39;s pretty simple although there are a few caveats. </p>
<p><a href="http://davidxmoody.com/host-any-static-site-with-github-pages/">Read 20 remaining paragraphs...</a></p>]]></description><link>http://davidxmoody.com/host-any-static-site-with-github-pages/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://davidxmoody.com/host-any-static-site-with-github-pages/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Switching from Jekyll to Metalsmith]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>Over the last couple of days, I have completely rewritten the source for this blog. Jekyll has been good to me for the last three months. However, I found myself wanting more control. I also wanted to be able to write extensions in JavaScript rather than Ruby. </p>
<p>This blog is now completely built by <a href="https://github.com/segmentio/metalsmith">Metalsmith</a>. It&#39;s a very simple static site generator. It&#39;s really just a way to help manipulate directories of files. All the interesting stuff is done by plugins, of which there are plenty.</p>
<p><a href="http://davidxmoody.com/switching-from-jekyll-to-metalsmith/">Read 3 remaining paragraphs...</a></p>]]></description><link>http://davidxmoody.com/switching-from-jekyll-to-metalsmith/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://davidxmoody.com/switching-from-jekyll-to-metalsmith/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Three months of blogging]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>This will be my third monthly review. Yet again, I am going to look back at the last month and create a plan for the next one. </p>
<p><a href="http://davidxmoody.com/three-months-of-blogging/">Read 15 remaining paragraphs...</a></p>]]></description><link>http://davidxmoody.com/three-months-of-blogging/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://davidxmoody.com/three-months-of-blogging/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[20 of my favourite cooking photos]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>I started learning to cook in September 2011. I really enjoyed it. I learned from my Mum, from books and from my own mistakes. </p>
<p>I started taking photographs of what I was making in early 2012. Since then, I have built up a collection of 550 cooking photos of new and interesting recipes. Unfortunately many of the early photos were taking with my Nexus One camera and are pretty much unusable. However, I still have plenty worth sharing, here are my 20 favourite cooking photos. </p>
<p><a href="http://davidxmoody.com/20-of-my-favourite-cooking-photos/">Read 40 remaining paragraphs...</a></p>]]></description><link>http://davidxmoody.com/20-of-my-favourite-cooking-photos/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://davidxmoody.com/20-of-my-favourite-cooking-photos/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Here are my dotfiles]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>I&#39;ve recently been uploading a lot of my old projects to GitHub. There is only one left: <strong>my dotfiles</strong>.</p>
<p><a href="http://davidxmoody.com/here-are-my-dotfiles/">Read 18 remaining paragraphs...</a></p>]]></description><link>http://davidxmoody.com/here-are-my-dotfiles/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://davidxmoody.com/here-are-my-dotfiles/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[A specific plan for next week]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>Three weeks ago, I wrote a <a href="http://davidxmoody.com/two-months-of-blogging/">two month review</a>. I said that I wanted to focus on <strong>getting a job</strong>.</p>
<p><a href="http://davidxmoody.com/a-specific-plan-for-next-week/">Read 9 remaining paragraphs...</a></p>]]></description><link>http://davidxmoody.com/a-specific-plan-for-next-week/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://davidxmoody.com/a-specific-plan-for-next-week/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[My 10 best Tenerife photos]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>In March of this year, I went on a family holiday with my parents to Tenerife. It was fantastic, one of the best holidays we have ever had. </p>
<p>That was also around the time I was getting into photography. I had just bought a second hand Fujifilm X10 and this was the first chance I had to really use it. I wanted to share some of my favourite photos. I&#39;ve probably got about 50 very good ones but that&#39;s too many for one blog post. So, here are my 10 best Tenerife photos.</p>
<p><a href="http://davidxmoody.com/my-10-best-tenerife-photos/">Read 10 remaining paragraphs...</a></p>]]></description><link>http://davidxmoody.com/my-10-best-tenerife-photos/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://davidxmoody.com/my-10-best-tenerife-photos/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[MCTS in Texas Hold 'em Poker: A retrospective]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>I&#39;ve recently been uploading a lot of my old projects. Both to prove I&#39;ve actually done them and also in case someone might be interested.</p>
<p>This week, I have uploaded my 3rd year Cambridge University dissertation project. It is a <strong>Texas Hold &#39;em poker-bot</strong> which uses the <strong>Monte Carlo Tree Search algorithm</strong>. You can <a href="https://github.com/davidxmoody/mctsbot">view the source on GitHub</a>. In this post, I am going to give a very brief summary of the project and make notes on how I could have done better.</p>
<p><a href="http://davidxmoody.com/mcts-in-texas-hold-em-poker-a-retrospective/">Read 20 remaining paragraphs...</a></p>]]></description><link>http://davidxmoody.com/mcts-in-texas-hold-em-poker-a-retrospective/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">http://davidxmoody.com/mcts-in-texas-hold-em-poker-a-retrospective/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>